Marketing professional, specializing in brand management and promotions through digital channels including digital publishing, search, social, and email. Expertise in project management, content creation, digital development, and analytical analysis for continuous improvement. Creates unique opportunities for brands to cultivate a voice while adhering to brand guidelines, budgets, and schedules. Adapts easily to changing targets, trends, and tech.

Experience

Senior Engineer-Digital Marketing, Mastercard, St. Louis, MO, September 2017 - Present

- Project Manager and Digital Strategist for launch and content creation promotion development of Mastercard online properties worldwide, including Mastercard, Masterpass, Priceless, and donation / charitable platforms.
- Works across multiple time zones and languages to ensure properties and promotions are launched properly, and continues to perform as planned. Analyse performance of campaigns from conception to decommission.
- Implemented a total rebranding of Mastercard.com across 88 countries. Moved sites to a unified CMS platform to streamline projects among international teams and ensure quality across all facets of our online presence.
- Manage our agile environment across teams worldwide by leading scrum meetings, planning sessions and brainstorms.

Digital Marketing Specialist, Saint Louis University, St. Louis, MO, January 2014 - August 2017

- Led digital marketing efforts (web, email, CRM, social media campaigns), as well as collaboration on traditional tactics.
- Develop and launch multi-channel campaigns for multiple programs, reaching diverse target markets including millennial students, young professionals, and B2B. Continually optimize campaigns using research and analytics.
- Manage staff, vendors, and budgets. Work with both internal teams and outside agencies to expand marketing efforts.
- Discovered new channels and tactics to reach our audience. Created and presented action plans to increase market presence, and report back to management with key progress indicators and strategies for continuous improvement.
- Implemented content marketing strategies and calendars. Organically increased audience 40% and reach 85%.
- Produce and manage content for digital channels, including blogs, press releases, infographics, and video content.
- Increased site traffic by 20% year to date, with peak increases in social, email, and organic search traffic.
- Maintain paid ad placements online, including search, banner ads, and retargeting. Develop strategies for long term branding initiatives and short term events. Optimized CPM and CPC while maintaining our target market.
- Manage CRM of over 30,000 contacts, maintained database accuracy while implementing automation techniques.

Marketing / Account Manager, The Able Few, St. Louis, MO, November 2012 - November 2013

- Managed marketing for digital development firm, including B2B, social media, press releases, and events.
- Worked in a continuous release cycle, where many hands were on a single project and concerted contact with the client was required to maintain the expected level of accuracy and excellence in our products.
- Developed business plans, site maps, and feature release timelines for web applications that have been featured at South By Southwest, Mashable.com, and other tech events and publications.
- Expanded outreach and followed various paths to connect with new business, including creating responses to RFP's, creating formal proposals for new projects, and attending networking events and one-on-one meetings.

Account Manager, CTM Media Group, St. Louis, MO, October 2011 - November 2012

- Managed over 400 traditional and digital advertising placements for area attractions and tourist hotspots.
- Introduced a new digital marketing medium to the St. Louis area. Facilitated placement in high end hotels and premium attractions. Increased digital reach in the St. Louis area to 2.5 million visitors annually.
- Created and presented analytical reports and research studies for our clients, showing where their marketing plan succeeded and giving insight on how to improve when needed.

Project Manager and Designer, 50 in the 314 (Freelance Consultancy), St. Louis, MO, January 2010 - Present

- Acts as consultant, designer / developer, and digital strategist for area advertising agencies (Scorch Agency, Osborn & Barr), startups, small businesses, political campaigns and local charities.
- Went one-on-one to discover client needs, develop strategies, and execute digital and traditional marketing campaigns.
- Managed multiple brands digital presence, including social, event, promotional tactics, and digital media buys.

Consumer Hospitality Representative, Anheuser-Busch, St. Louis, MO, September 2006 - September 2011

- Acted as brand ambassador for guests of Anheuser-Busch at the St. Louis Tour Center.
- Coordinated projects among the staff, kept programs and day to day tasks running smoothly and efficiently.
- Promoted to Guest Service Specialist in fall of 2008.

Proficiencies

- Digital Marketing Analytics (Google), Salesforce, Email (Mailchimp), Social Managers (Hootsuite, Radian6).
- Media Buying AdSense, AdWords, Social Media including Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Instagram.
- Media Production Expertise in Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, and Final Cut Pro.
- Development Full Wordpress Builds, Read and Write CSS, PHP & Ruby, Operates well in most CMS's.
- Business Microsoft Office Suite, Basecamp and Tableau. Managed 30,000+ contact Salesforce database.

Education

Saint Louis University - St. Louis, MO MBA - Marketing Focus, May 2017

Webster University - St. Louis, MO BA - Advertising and Marketing Communications, Graduated with honors, May 2010